window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "C_Programming - Function — Slot 5 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Function — Slot 5",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>What is the value of F(4) using the following procedure:<br><pre><code>function F(K : integer)\ninteger;\nbegin\nif (k&lt;3) then F:=k else F:=F(k-1)*F(k-2)+F(k-3)\nend; </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>6</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>7</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>8</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>5</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/50136/isro2008-69\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C function:<br><pre><code> int f(int n)\n{\n    static int i = 1;\n    if(n &gt;= 5) return n;\n    n = n+i;\n    i++;\n    return f(n);\n}</code></pre> <br>\nThe value returned by f(1) is: <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>6</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>7</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>8</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>7</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1028/gate2004-31-isro2008-40\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider the code fragment written in C below :<br><pre><code>void f (int n)\n{ \n    if (n &lt;= 1)  {\n        printf (\"%d\", n);\n    }\n    else {\n        f (n/2);\n        printf (\"%d\", n%2);\n    }\n}</code></pre> Which of the following implementations will produce the same output for f(173) as the above code?<br>P1<br><pre><code>void f (int n)\n{ \n    if (n/2)  {\n        f(n/2);\n    }\n    printf (\"%d\", n%2);\n}</code></pre> <br>P2<br><pre><code> void f (int n)\n{ \n    if (n &lt;=1)  {\n        printf (\"%d\", n);\n    }\n    else {\n        printf (\"%d\", n%2);\n        f (n/2);\n    }\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Both P1 and P2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>P2 only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>P1 only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither P1 nor P2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>P1 only</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3407/gate2008-it-83\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Consider the code fragment written in C below :<pre><code> void f (int n)\n{ \n  if (n &lt;=1)  {\n   printf (\"%d\", n);\n  }\n  else {\n   f (n/2);\n   printf (\"%d\", n%2);\n  }\n}</code></pre> <br>What does f(173) print? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>10110101</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>010101101</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>010110101</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>10101101</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>10101101</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3406/gate2008-it-82\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Consider the C program below. What does it print?<pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\n# define swapl (a, b) tmp = a; a = b; b = tmp\nvoid swap2 ( int a, int b)\n{\n        int tmp;\n        tmp = a; a = b; b = tmp;\n }\nvoid swap3 (int*a, int*b)\n{\n        int tmp;\n        tmp = *a; *a = *b; *b = tmp;\n}\nint main ()\n{\n        int num1 = 5, num2 = 4, tmp;\n        if (num1 &lt; num2) {swap1 (num1, num2);}\n        if (num1 &lt; num2) {swap2 (num1 + 1, num2);}\n        if (num1 &gt; = num2) {swap3 (&amp;num1, &amp;num2);}\n        printf (\"%d, %d\", num1, num2);\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>5,5</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>5,4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>4,5</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>4,4</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>4,5</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3360/gate2008-it-50\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C functions:<pre><code>int f1(int n)\n{\n  if(n == 0 || n == 1)\n    return n;\n  else\n    return (2*f1(n-1) + 3*f1(n-2));\n}\n \nint f2(int n)\n{\n  int i;\n  int X[N], Y[N], Z[N] ;\n  X[0] = Y[0] = Z[0] = 0;\n  X[1] = 1; Y[1] = 2; Z[1] = 3;\n  for(i = 2; i &lt;= n; i++)\n  {\n    X[i] = Y[i-1] + Z[i-2];\n    Y[i] = 2*X[i];\n    Z[i] = 3*X[i];\n  }\n  return X[n] ;\n}</code></pre> f1(8) and f2(8) return the values <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1661 and 1640</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>59 and 59</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1640 and 1640</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1640 and 1661</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>1640 and 1640</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43489/gate2008-75#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct option to fill ? 1 and ? 2 so that the program below prints an\ninput string in reverse order. Assume that the input string is terminated by a\nnewline character.<pre><code> void recerse void {\n   int c;\n   if (?1) reverse ();\n   ?2\n}\nmain {\n    printf(\"Enter Text \"); printf(\"\\ n\") ;\n    reverse();  printf(\"\\ n\");\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>?1 is (getchar ( )! = '\\ n') <br>\n?2 is getchar (c);</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>?1 is (c = getchar ( ) )! = '\\ n')<br>\n?2 is getchar (c);</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>?1 is (c ! = '\\ n')<br>\n?2 is putchar (c);</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>?1 is ((c = getchar ( ) )! = '\\ n') <br>\n?2 is putchar (c);</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>?1 is ((c = getchar ( ) )! = '\\ n') <br>\n?2 is putchar (c);</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/484/gate2008-61#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>What is printed by the following C program?<pre><code> int f(int x, int *py, int **ppz)\t\t\t\n{\t\t\t\t\t\t                    \t\n    int y, z;\t\t\t\t\t                \t\t\n    **ppz += 1; z = **ppz;\t\t                \n    *py += 2; y = *py;\t\t\t\t\t                \t\n    x += 3;\t\t\t\t\t                    \t\n    return x+y+z;\n}\n\nvoid main()\n{\n    int c, *b, **a;\n    c = 4; b = &amp;c; a = &amp;b;\n    printf(\"%d\", f(c, b, a));\n    \t\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>18</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>19</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>21</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>22</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>19</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/483/gate2008-60#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Study the following program<br><pre><code>//precondition: x&gt;=0\npublic void demo(int x)\n{\n    System.out.print(x % 10); \n    if (x % 10 != 0)\n    {\n        demo(x/10);\n    }\n    System.out.print(x%10);\n} </code></pre> <br>\nWhich of the following is printed as a result of the call demo (1234)? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1441</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3443</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>12344321</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>43211234</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>43211234</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49496/isro2007-23\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider the program below in a hypothetical programming language which allows global variables and a choice of static or dynamic scoping.<br><pre><code>int i ;\nprogram main ()\n{\n    i = 10;\n    call f();\n}\n\nprocedure f()\n{   \n    int i = 20;\n    call g ();\n}\nprocedure g ()\n{   \n    print i;\n} </code></pre> <br>Let x be the value printed under static scoping and y be the value printed under dynamic scoping. Then, x and y are: <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>x=10, y=20</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>x=20, y=10</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>x=10, y=10</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>x=20, y=20</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>x=10, y=20</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3467/gate2007-it-34-ugcnet-dec2012-iii-52\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Consider the program below in a hypothetical language which allows global variable and a choice of call by reference or call by value methods of parameter passing. <br><pre><code>int i ;\nprogram main ()\n{\n    int j = 60;\n    i = 50;\n    call f (i, j);\n    print i, j;\n}\nprocedure f (x, y)\n{           \n    i = 100;\n    x = 10;\n    y = y + i ;\n} </code></pre> <br>Which one of the following options represents the correct output of the program for the two parameter passing mechanisms? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Call by value : i = 70, j = 10; Call by reference :i = 60, j = 70</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Call by value : i = 50, j = 60; Call by reference :i = 50, j = 70</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Call by value : i = 10, j = 70; Call by reference :i = 100, j = 60</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Call by value : i = 100, j = 60; Call by reference :i = 10, j = 70</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Call by value : i = 100, j = 60; Call by reference :i = 10, j = 70</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3466/gate2007-it-33\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>The function f is defined as follows:<br><pre><code> int f (int n) {\n    if (n &lt;= 1) return 1;\n    else if (n % 2  ==  0) return f(n/2);\n    else return f(3n - 1);\n}</code></pre> <br>\nAssuming that arbitrarily large integers can be passed as a parameter to the function, consider the following statements.<br><br>i. The function f terminates for finitely many different values of \\(n \\geq 1\\).<br>\nii. The function f terminates for infinitely many different values of \\(n \\geq 1\\).<br>\niii. The function f does not terminate for finitely many different values of \\(n \\geq 1\\).<br>\niv. The function f does not terminate for infinitely many different values of \\(n \\geq 1\\).<br><br>\nWhich one of the following options is true of the above? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>i and iii</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>i and iv</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>ii and iii</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>ii and iv</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>ii and iv</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3460/gate2007-it-27\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C function:<pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint f(int n)\n{\n    static int r = 0;\n    if (n &lt;= 0) return 1;\n    if (n &gt; 3)\n    {\n        r = n;\n        return f(n-2)+2;\n    }\n    return f(n-1)+r;\n}\n \nint main()\n{\n    printf(\"%d\", f(5));\n} </code></pre>\nWhat is the value of f(5)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>7</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>9</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>18</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>18</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1240/gate2007-42#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>The following function computes the value of  \\(\\binom{m}{n}\\) correctly for all legal values \\(m\\) and \\(n\\) \\( (m \\geq 1, n \\geq 0 \\text{ and } m \\gt n)\\)<pre><code> int func(int m, int n)\n{\n    if (E) return 1;\n    else return(func(m -1, n) + func(m - 1, n - 1));\n}</code></pre>In the above function, which of the following is the correct expression for E? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(n = = 0) || (m = = 1)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(n = = 0) &amp;&amp; (m = = 1)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(n = = 0) || (m = = n)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>(n = = 0) &amp;&amp; (m = = n)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>(n = = 0) || (m = = n)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3595/gate2006-it-52\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the choices given below would be printed when the following program is executed?<br><pre><code>#include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nvoid swap (int *x, int *y)\n{\n    static int *temp;\n    temp = x;\n    x = y;\n    y = temp;\n}\nvoid printab ()\n{\n    static int i, a = -3, b = -6;\n    i = 0;\n    while (i &lt;= 4)\n    {\n        if ((i++)%2 == 1) continue;\n        a = a + i;\n        b = b + i;\n    }\n    swap (&amp;a, &amp;b);\n    printf(\"a =  %d, b = %d\\n\", a, b);\n}\nmain()\n{\n    printab();\n    printab();\n} </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>a = 0, b = 3\na = 0, b = 3</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>a = 3, b = 0\na = 12, b = 9</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>a = 3, b = 6\na = 3, b = 6</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>a = 6, b = 3\na = 15, b = 12</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>a = 6, b = 3\na = 15, b = 12</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3593/gate2006-it-50\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
